Finding Aid for Livonia Citizens For Better Human Relations (Mich.) records, 1963-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Livonia Citizens For Better Human Relations (Mich.) records 1963-1976
Livonia Citizens For Better Human Relations (Mich.)
0.5 linear feet
91464 Bj 2
Livonia, Michigan human rights organization; administrative files, correspondence, topical files, newsletters, and newspaper clippings relating to activities of the organization.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Doris and Winthrop Sears (Donor No. 7886 ) in November 1990.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Livonia Citizens for Better Human Relations (LCBHR) was founded in September 1963, incorporated in January 1964, and dissolved in March 1976. The organization met monthly in local religious buildings, and membership was open to all persons living or working in the city or school district of Livonia, Michigan.
The purpose of the organization was to "promote good will, understanding and respect for human dignity as well as for the law among present and future members of this community regardless of their race, color, religion, or national origin" through a variety of activities. These activities included publishing a monthly newsletter, establishing a Students Committee for Better Human Relations, and sponsoring lectures and guest speakers on the issues of civil rights, equal housing, and busing to increase public awareness and encourage peaceful inter-racial relations. In 1969 they organized a local boycott of California grapes in support of migrant workers. Representatives of the organization corresponded with local politicians and community leaders, as well as state senators and representatives, expressing their concerns and urging reform.
The records of the Livonia Citizens for Better Human Relations contain rich information relating to race relations in the Livonia community during the years 1963 to 1976. The organization's activities are best documented in the extensive Meeting Minutes and Newsletters. The efforts of LCBHR members to discourage prejudice and discrimination within the community are documented in letters to various political figures in the Correspondence, Topical Files, Newspaper Clippings, and Newsletters files.
Subjects:
Social action--Michigan--Societies, etc.; Civil rights--Michigan--Livonia.; Livonia (Mich.); Livonia Citizens for Better Human Relations (Mich.)
- Organization files
  - Administrative Files
    - Articles of Incorporation and Constitution (Box 1)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1963-1976, 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Membership, 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1973, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Topical Files
    - Civil Rights (Box 1)
    - Equal Housing (Box 1)
    - Grape Boycott/Migrant Workers (Box 1)
    - Northwest Inter-faith Center for Racial Justice (Box 1)
    - Other Human Relations Organizations (Box 1)
    - Schools (Box 1)
    - Students Committee for Better Human Relations (SCBHR) (Box 1)
    - Wayne County Millage Proposals (Box 1)
  - Newsletters, 1966-1976, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1967-1974 (Box 1)